Register of the Mexican subject collection, 1918-1998
Hoover Institution Archives
Mexican Subject Collection,
1918-1998
89001
36 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 5 microfilm reels, 1 phonorecord, 2 maps (20 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, policy statements, resolutions, bulletins, speeches, agenda, election material, serial issues, pamphlets, and other printed matter, relating to political conditions in Mexico. The collection focuses primarily on communist, socialist and Trotskyist organizations in Mexico, and consists largely of issuances of these organizations (especially the Partido Comunista Mexicano, the Partido Mexicano de los Trabajadores, the Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores, and the Partido Socialista Unificado de México) and of trade unions (especially of university workers) from the 1960s through the 1980s.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1989.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Mexico; Mexico --Politics and government --20th century; Communism --Mexico; Socialism --Mexico; Fourth International; Communism; Trade-unions --Mexico; Universities and colleges --Mexico; Partido Comunista Mexicano; Partido Mexicano de los Trabajadores; Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores (Mexico); Partido Socialista Unificado de México; Phonorecords
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1925-1994. (Boxes 1-35)
  Reports, policy statements, meeting material, election material, contracts, bulletins, clippings, speeches, budgets, press releases, agenda, pamphlets, by-laws, petitions, circulars, printed articles, resolutions, leaflets, serial issues, flyers, lists, forms, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1931-1988. (Boxes 36-38)
  Flyers, handbills, and serial issues; primarily Trotskyist and communist publications
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1918-1975. (Microfilm cabinet, Map cabinet, Record cabinet)
  Five rolls of microfilm, one phonorecord, and two maps showing land ownership in portions of Mexico
Container List
Check card catalog for increments that may have been received after December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1925-1994
  - General. Serial issues, 1968-1987 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Accion Proletaria. Serial issues, 1971-1972 (Folder 2)
  - Agrarian organizations. Flyers, clippings, declarations, leaflets, pamphlets, conference material, by-laws, newsletters, and reports, 1973-1985. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 3-4)
  - Argentina. Clipping and pamphlet, 1972-1975 (Folder 5)
  - Asamblea Nacional Obrera Campesina y Popular. Flyers and resolutions, 1983-1984 (Folder 6)
  - Asociacion Civica Nacional Revolucionaria. Declarations, pamphlets, serial issues, flyers, and circulars, 1972-1983 (Folder 7)
  - Baja California. Newsletters, 1976-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Central America. Serial issue and pamphlet, 1980-1981 (Folder 9)
  - Centro Libre de Experimentacion Teatral y Artistica. Program statement, flyers, and newsletters, 1975-1977 (Folder 10)
  - Comandos Armados del Pueblo. Circulars and clippings, 1971 (Folder 11)
  - Communism. SEE ALSO: Labor; also specific organizations
    - General. Reports, position statements, pamphlets, serial issues, flyers, circulars, charts, clipping, ca. 1930-1986 (Folder 12)
    - General (Box 2., Folder 1-2)
    - International. Pamphlets, flyer, and serial issues, 1934-1984 (Folder 3)
    - Latin America. Reports, mimeograph copy of Jose Arico, "El Comunismo Latinoamericano," printed excerpt of Julio Cuadros Caldas, El Comunismo Criollo, mimeograph report, El Eurocomunismo y America Latina, printed articles, serial issues, conference material, leaflets, flyers, and circulars, 1960-1981 (Folder 4-6)
    - Latin America (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - Confederacion de Trabajadores de Mexico/Congreso del Trabajo. Conference material and clippings, 1975-1978 (Folder 2)
  - Coordinacion Proletaria. Serial issue, 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Corriente Socialista
    - General. Policy statements, resolutions, pamphlets, circulars, and reports, 1980-1982 (Folder 4)
    - Tribuna Proletaria. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
  - Economic conditions. Clippings, pamphlet, and reports by primarily leftist analysts, 1975-1985 (Folder 5)
  - Federacion Latinoamericana de Periodistas. Newsletters and a pamphlet, 1976-1978 (Folder 6)
  - Federacion Nacional de Organizaciones Bolcheviques. Newsletters and a clipping, 1981 (Folder 7)
  - Fourth International. Bulletins, circulars, position statements, serial issues, circulars, pamphlets, flyers, and leaflets, 1935-1976. Primarily relates to miscellaneous Trotskyist organizations. SEE ALSO: Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores (PRT), Liga Obrera Marxista (LOM), Partido Obrero Socialista (POS), and Liga Socialista (LS) (Folder 8)
  - Frente Estudiantil Revolucionario. Report and policy statement, 1971 (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - Frente Estudiantil Socialista. Newsletter, 1970 (Folder 2)
  - Frente Juventil Ferrocarrilero. Newsletters, 1973 (Folder 3)
  - Frente Marxista. Pamphlets, policy statements, meeting materials, declarations, circulars, newsletters, reports, bulletins, and resolutions, 1975-1981 (Folder 4-5)
  - Frente Nacional de Accion Popular. Flyer, clipping, and position statement, 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Frente Obrero. Letter to the DF committee of the Partido Comunista Mexicano (PCM), 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Frente Sindical Independiente. Program statements and serial issue, 1974-1977 (Folder 8)
  - Frente Urbano Zapatista. Policy statements, reports, and a clipping, 1972-1973 (Folder 9)
  - Grupo Comunista Internacionalista. Discussion material, reports, circulars, flyers, and newsletters, 1972-1976. SEE ALSO: NOTE relating to the Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores (Folder 10-11)
  - Grupo Estudiantil Revolucionario. Newsletters ("El Sendero"), 1978-1980 (Box 5., Folder 1)
  - Grupo V.I. Lenin. Program statement and newsletters ("Revista Leninista"), 1974-1986 (Folder 2)
  - "Hoja Popular". Newsletters, ca. 1970 (Folder 3)
  - Junta de Coordinacion Revolucionaria. Serial issues, 1977 (Folder 4)
  - Juventud Marxista Revolucionaria. Circular and newsletters ("Virus Rojo"), ca. 1973 (Folder 5)
  - Labor. NOTE: Most of this material relates to trade unions and radical syndicalist movements
    - General. Mimeograph copy of Jose Villasenor, "El Control Estatal del Movimiento Obrero, 1900-1917," newsletters, reports, political platforms, circulars, position statements, bulletins, serial issues, clippings, flyers, and pamphlets, 1963-1987 (Folder 6-7)
    - Communications workers. Clippings, position statements, pamphlet, conference material, and serial issue, 1975-1979 (Folder 8)
    - Educational workers. Bulletins, pamphlets, conference material, flyers, and miscellany, 1960-1987 (Box 6., Folder 1)
    - Electrical workers. Reports, clippings, flyers, bulletins, circulars, serial issues, position statements, conference material, newsletters, and pamphlets, 1966-1986. Primarily relates to the Sindicato Unico de Trabajadores Electricistas de la Republica Mexicana (SUTERM) (Folder 2-6)
    - Government workers. Newsletters and flyers, 1975-1984 (Box 7., Folder 1)
    - Health care workers. Reports, newsletters, and pamphlet, 1975-1976 (Folder 2)
    - Mining and metallurgical workers. Clippings, pamphlets, and flyers, 1975-1981 (Folder 3)
    - Petroleum workers. Mimeograph copy of Julio Valdivieso Castillo, "Historia del Movimiento Sindical Petrolero en Minatitlan, Veracruz,", program statement, newsletters, and clippings, 1963-1983 (Folder 4)
    - Transport workers
      - General. Clippings and flyers, 1975 (Folder 5)
      - Railways. Flyers, circulars, report, press release, leaflet, and newsletters, 1959-1983. Includes material relating to the Movimiento Sindical Ferrocarrilero (Folder 6-7)
  - Lacandones. Statement on political prisoners and circulars, 1973 (Folder 8)
  - Liga Comunista 23 de Septiembre
    - General. Policy statements, clippings, circulars, pamphlets, serial issues, and flyers; includes a book, Manifiesto al Proletariado de la Liga Comunista 23 de Septiembre and La Liga Comunista 23 de Septiembre: Origenes y Naufragio by Gustavo Hirales Moran, 1972-1983 (Folder 9-10)
    - "Madera". Newsletters, 1972-1980 (Box 8., Folder 1)
  - Liga Comunista Internacionalista. Resolutions, meeting material, and newsletters, 1974-1976. SEE ALSO: NOTE relating to the Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores (Folder 2)
  - Liga Obrera Marxista. Position statements, and newsletters ("Boletin Obrero"); SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 3)
  - Liga Socialista. SEE ALSO: NOTE relating to the Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores
    - General. Resolutions, bulletins, meeting material, newsletters, and flyers, 1973-1975 (Folder 4)
    - El Socialista (Clave). SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
  - "Lucha Popular". Newsletters, and pamphlet, 1970-1979 (Folder 5)
  - Movimiento de Accion Revolucionaria. Clippings and circulars, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - Movimiento de Accion y Unidad Socialista. Flyers, newsletters, printed articles, pamphlet, policy statements, flyers, and resolutions; includes material relating to the Movimiento de Organizacion Socialista and the Partido Socialista Revolucionario, 1970-1980. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 7)
  - Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria Estudiantil- Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria. Circulars, policy statements, reports, notes, serial issues, newsletters, flyers, minutes, pamphlet, clippings, and miscellany, 1967-1983 (Folder 8)
  - Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria Estudiantil- Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria (Box 9., Folder 1-3)
  - Movimiento Revolucionario del Magisterio. Flyers, leaflets, newsletters, resolutions, program statements, reports, and pamphlets, 1969-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Movimiento Revolucionario del Pueblo
    - General. Pamphlets, policy statements, reports, leaflets, and newsletters, 1967-1983 (Folder 5)
    - El Trabajador. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
  - Movimiento Revolucionario 8 de Octubre. Reports, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Movimiento Sindical de Trabajadores de la Secretaria de Agricultura y Recursos Hidraulicos. Newsletters ("La Semilla"), 1983 (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - Movimiento Urbano Popular. Report and newsletter, 1983 (Folder 2)
  - Nicaragua. Newsletters, reports, flyers, and circulars; relates to solidarity with the Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional (FSLN), 1976-1986 (Folder 3)
  - Organizacion Comunista Proletaria. Newsletters ("Proletariado y Revolucion"). SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
  - Organizacion de Izquierda Revolucionaria-Linea de Masas. Reports, by-laws, resolutions, leaflets, and clippings, 1982-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Organizacion Revolucionaria del Proletariado
    - General. Policy statement, 1978 (Folder 5)
    - "Camaradas". Newsletters, 1980-1981 (Folder 6)
  - Partido Accion Nacional. Clipping, pamphlets, periodicals, 1979-1994 (Folder 7)
  - Partido Comunista de Mexico (Marxista-Leninista). Newsletters, flyers and leaflet concerning Chiapas rebellion, 1979-1994 (Folder 8)
  - Partido Comunista Mexicano
    - General. Policy statements, circulars, discussion bulletins, correspondence, mimeograph memoir, reports, leaflets, and pamphlets, 1921-1981 (Folder 9-11)
    - Central Committee. Clippings, reports, policy statements, minutes, meeting material, newsletters, pamphlets, resolutions, circulars, declarations, flyers, and election material, 1925-1982 (Box 11., Folder 1-9)
    - Central Committee (Box 12., Folder 1-4)
    - Electoral activity. Clippings, flyers, schedule, and outline, 1976 (Folder 5)
    - Labor
      - General. Pamphlets, reports relating to strategy, and conference material, 1957-1982 (Folder 6-9)
      - Educational workers. Discussion material and a newsletter. SEE ALSO: PCM/University organizations, PCM/Youth movements/Juventud Comunista Mexicana, and Student movements; also OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 10)
      - Electrical workers. Flyers, ca. 1975 (Folder 11)
      - Railway workers. Pamphlets, 1965-1986 (Folder 12)
      - Textile workers. Newsletters, circular, and a pamphlet, 1973 (Folder 13)
    - National Assembly
      - General. Pamphlets and resolutions, 1974 (Box 13., Folder 1)
      - Liberacion. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
    - National Congresses. Reports, resolutions, instructions, and clippings, 1926-1944, 1977 (Folder 2-5)
    - Political reform. Report, newsletter, and flyer, 1964-ca. 1980 (Folder 6)
    - Regional organizations. Meeting material, circulars, reports, flyers, position statements, reports, agenda, clippings, letters, notes, and miscellany, 1958-1981. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE
      - Baja California (Folder 7)
      - Chihuahua (Folder 8)
      - Coahuila (Folder 9)
      - Guerrero (Folder 10)
      - Jalisco (Folder 11)
      - Morelos (Folder 12)
      - Nuevo Leon (Folder 13)
      - Puebla (Folder 14-15)
      - Sinaloa (Folder 16)
      - Valle de Mexico (including the Federal District) (Box 14., Folder 1-6)
      - Valle de Mexico (Box 15., Folder 1)
      - Yucatan (Folder 2)
    - University organizations. Discussion material, position statements, circulars, reports, clippings, newsletters, notes, holograph and typescript studies, pamphlets, and resolutions, 1972-1981. Primarily relates to the PCM group at the Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico (UNAM) (Folder 3-5)
    - Youth organizations
      - General. Conference material, circular, report, and newsletter, 1929-1981 (Folder 6)
      - Juventud Comunista de Mexico. Serial issues, reports, bulletins, circulars, position statements, flyers, notes, conference material, and pamphlet, 1967-1981 (Box 16., Folder 1-2)
  - Partido de la Clase Obrera Mexicana. Pamphlets, position papers, flyers, reports, circulars, and newsletters (El Organizador Socialista), 1972-1977 (Folder 3)
  - Partido de la Revolucion Democratica. Pamphlets, 1990-1992 (Folder 4)
  - Partido de la Revolucion Social. Position statements, conference material, flyers, pamphlets, reports, and newsletters, 1985-1988 (Folder 5)
  - Partido de los Pobres. Clippings, circulars, and a report; includes material relating to the kidnapping of A. Martinez Verdugo and Felix Bautista, 1972-1986 (Box 17., Folder 1-2)
  - Partido del Pueblo Mexicano. Position papers, newsletters, and circulars, 1975-1984. Includes material relating to the Partido Popular Socialista and the Union General de Obreros y Campesinos de Mexico (Folder 3)
  - Partido Mexicano de los Trabajadores
    - General. Reports, policy statements, circulars, election material, letter, pamphlets, clippings, meeting material, newsletters, flyers, cartoons, forms, and miscellany; includes material relating to PEMEX, women, youth, economics, education, agrarian activities, and regional groups in Puebla, Mexico and D.F., 1975-1985 (Folder 4-11)
    - General (Box 18., Folder 1-4)
    - Insurgencia Popular, 1973-1983 (Folder 5-7)
    - Insurgencia Popular, 1983-1985 (Box 19., Folder 1)
    - El Libertario. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
    - "Semanario," 1982-1984 (Folder 2-4)
    - "Semanario," 1984-1985 (Box 20., Folder 1)
  - Partido Obrero Socialista. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
  - Partido Popular Socialista. Conference material, position papers, reports, poems, newsletters, electoral platform, flyers, serial issue, pamphlets, and by-laws, 1934-1976. Includes material relating to Juventud Popular Socialista (Folder 2)
  - Partido Proletario. Voz Proletaria. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
  - Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores. NOTE: The PRT resulted from a succession of fusions involving the Grupo Comunista Internacionalista (GCI), the Liga Comunista Internacional (LCI), and the Liga Socialista (LS). In general, material which spans these changes, particularly serials, has been arranged here, while earlier material may also be found under separate headings for the predecessor organizations
    - General. Newsletters, circulars, policy statements, reports, election materials, declarations, discussion bulletins, minutes, flyers, leaflets, pamphlets, clippings, and resolutions, 1971-1987 (Folder 3-4)
    - General (Box 21., Folder 1-2)
    - Bandera Roja. SEE: OVERSIZE FILE
    - La Internacional. Newsletters, 1969-1977 (Folder 3-4)
  - Partido Revolucionario Institucional (PRI). Pamphlets containing party documents and material concerning the presidential candidacies of Luis Donaldo Colosio and Ernesto Zedillo, 1993-1994 (Box 35., Folder 5)
  - Partido Revolucionario Obrero. Voz Obrera, 1968-1971 (Box 21., Folder 5)
  - Partido Revolucionario Obrero Clandestino Union del Pueblo-Frente Nacional Democratico Popular. Policy statements, circulars, and a report on political repression, 1977-1983 (Folder 6)
  - Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores. Conference material, program statements, resolutions, press release, flyers, reports, and by-laws, 1973-1981 (Box 22., Folder 1)
  - Partido Socialista Revolucionario. Newsletters, program statements, resolutions, bulletins, speeches and writings, agenda and minutes, flyers, pamphlets, and clipping, 1974-1980 (Folder 2)
  - Partido Socialista Unificado de Mexico. Reports, policy statements, declarations, leaflets, meeting material, resolutions, flyers, newsletters, election material, letters, forms, serial issues, circulars, clippings, agenda, pamphlets, and miscellany, 1982-1987. Includes material relating to the history of the party, conferences, and regional organizations (Folder 3-4)
  - Partido Socialista Unificado de Mexico (Box 23., Folder 1-5)
  - Partido Socialista Unificado de Mexico (Box 24., Folder 1-8)
  - Partido Socialista Unificado de Mexico (Box 25., Folder 1-4)
  - Partido Socialista Unificado de Mexico (Box 26., Folder 1-4)
  - Partido Socialista Unificado de Mexico (Box 27., Folder 1-2)
  - Politics and government. Election reports, press releases, speeches by Carlos Salinas de Gortari, and clippings, 1975-1992 (Folder 3)
  - Prisoners and human rights. Reports, policy statements, by-laws, printed articles, clipping, lists, circulars, flyers, pamphlet, agenda, and speeches, 1969-1983. Primarily material relating to conferences of the Foro Nacional por la Amnistia General y la Presentacion de los Desaparecidos Politicos, 1969-1983 (Folder 4-6)
  - Railways. Financial reports for the Mexican Railway Company, Ltd., and a photocopy of a book by Antonio E. Vera entitled Arena en los Zapatos, 1943-1954 (Folder 7)
  - Recuento. Serial issues of Recuento, 1979-1980 (Box 28., Folder 1)
  - "Socialismo Obrero". Newsletters, 1974 (Folder 2)
  - Student movements. Conference material, circulars, program statements, newsletters, resolutions, pamphlets, bulletins, and flyers, 1966-1978 (Folder 3)
  - Union de Lucha Revolucionaria. Newsletters, 1982-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Union del Pueblo. Policy statements, report, pamphlet, and circulars, 1976-1979 (Folder 5)
  - Union Nacional de Izquierda Revolucionaria. Policy statements and a leaflet, ca. 1985 (Folder 6)
  - University organizations
    - Federacion de Sindicatos de Trabajadores Universitarios (FSTU). Newsletters, flyers, program statements, and resolutions, 1978 (Folder 7)
    - Sindicato Unico Nacional de Trabajadores Universitarios (SUNTU). Meeting material, speech, pamphlets, and newsletters, 1979-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Universidad Autonoma de Guerrero. Policy statements, circulars, and flyers, 1979-1980. Primarily relates to the Union Sindical de Catedraticos de la Universidad Autonoma de Guerrero (Box 29., Folder 1)
  - Universidad Autonoma de Puebla
    - General. Flyers and leaflets, n.d. (Folder 2)
    - Sindicato Unico de Trabajadores de Universidad Autonoma de Puebla
      - General. Policy statements, reports, contracts, meeting material, by-laws, petitions, pamphlets, circulars, clippings, agenda, and flyers, 1973-1987 (Folder 3-5)
      - General (Box 30., Folder 1-6)
      - Corriente Renovacion Social. Flyers, circulars, and miscellany, 1986 (Folder 7)
      - Corriente Sindical Roja. Policy statements, circulars, and newsletters, 1976-1977 (Folder 8)
      - Tendencia Sindical Democratica. Policy statements, report, circulars, and newsletters, 1976-1978 (Folder 9)
  - Universidad Autonoma Metropolitana. Conference material, newsletters, reports, and flyers, 1976-1977. Relates to the PCM and the Sindicato Independiente de Trabajadores de la Universidad Autonoma Metropolitana (Box 31., Folder 1-2)
  - Universidad de las Americas. Sindicato de Trabajadores y Empleados de la Universidad de las Americas. Circulars and flyers, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico (UNAM)
    - General. Includes material relating to FSTU, SUNTU, STEUNAM, SPAUNAM, and STUNAM. Policy statements, reports, resolutions, by-laws, circulars, flyers, pamphlets, meeting material, newsletters, and miscellany, 1972-1986 (Folder 4-5)
    - Sindicato del Personal Academico de la UNAM (SPAUNAM). Policy statements, circulars, by-laws, newsletters, contracts, reports, bulletins, meeting material, clippings, pamphlets, flyers, and miscellany, 1973-1977 (Folder 6-8)
    - Sindicato del Personal Academico de la UNAM (SPAUNAM) (Box 32., Folder 1-4)
    - Sindicato del Personal Academico de la UNAM (SPAUNAM) (Box 33., Folder 1-3)
    - Sindicato de Trabajadores y Empleados de la UNAM (STEUNAM). Clippings, bulletins, circulars, meeting material, and newsletters, 1967-1975 (Folder 4-5)
    - Sindicato de Trabajadores de la UNAM (STUNAM). Policy statements, meeting material, reports, circulars, flyers, newsletters, bulletins, clippings, by-laws, pamphlets, and budgets, 1974-1982 (Folder 6)
    - Sindicato de Trabajadores de la UNAM (STUNAM) (Box 34., Folder 1-6)
    - Sindicato de Trabajadores de la UNAM (STUNAM) (Box 35., Folder 1-2)
    - Sindicato de Trabajadores de la UNAM (STUNAM). Delegacion de la Facultad de Ciencias Politicas y Sociales. Position papers, circulars, by-laws, pamphlet, reports, and newsletters, 1976-1981. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 3)
  - World War II. Flyers, leaflets, clippings, letters, newsletters, reports, circulars, press releases, and miscellany, 1941-1943. Primarily anti-fascist material SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 4)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1931-1988. Flyers, handbills, and serial issues.
  - Primarily Trotskyist and communist publications (Box 36-39.)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1918-1975
  - Five rolls of microfilm. Serials include El Machete, Tierra, Teoria, La Correspondance Internationale; subjects include education, agrarian issues, and politics in Yucatan. Itemized list available (Oversize Microfilm cabinet)
  - One phonorecord entitled Mexico, Days of Struggle, 1973 (Oversize Phonorecord cabinet)
  - Two maps relating to land ownership (Oversize Map cabinet)